NOURAN ALI

Email: nouran578@gmail.com

(3)

+971 50 587 5367

0

Abu Dhabi, UAE

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Markup Languages: HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, PHP, JavaScript, and jQuery
- CMS: WordPress
- Framework: jQuery and jQuery UI
- Server Technologies: Node.js and Firebase
- Fluency in C++, C#, Java, Python, Dart, Flutter, SQL, and NoSQL
- Version Management: Git and GitHub
- Scripting Languages : PHP, Python, JavaScript
- UI/UX Tools: Adobe XD, Figma, and JustInMind
- 3D Visualization: Blender and Maya
- Visual Effects: Unreal and Unity
- MS Office
- Other: npm

EDUCATION

Heriot-Watt University

Dubai, UAE (09/2019 - 07/2023)

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

- Degree Awarded with Honours
- Academic Merit Scholarship, 2019 -2023 from Heriot-Watt University

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Associate in Python Programming, Cisco Networking Academy - 2021
- Microsoft Azure Al Fundamentals (Al-900), Microsoft - 2023

CAREER OVERVIEW

I am a passionate front-end web developer. I primarily focus on writing clean, elegant, and efficient code. I am proficient in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Over the past two (2) years, I have primarily worked for companies that specialize in enterprise web and phone applications development. Participated in development and implementation of web-based soultions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Intern - Tornado Technology Services Abu Dhabi, UAE - (08/2022 - 07/2023)

- Developed prototypes and mockups for new features, enhancing UX and UI design. Developing responsive web applications across platforms and mobile apps using JavaScript, jQuery in frontend. Worked with a team of developers to resolve front-end and CSS issues.
- Responsible for implementation of new mainframe development project. ■ Successfully integrated websites with powerful backend services such as databases, APIs, and other services using mySQL.

Front-End Developer Intern - KBC Technologies Abu Dhabi, UAE - (12/2021 - 05/2022)

- Turn design pages and specific components into HTML,CSS, and JavaScript.
 Developed and maintained legacy applications.
- Analyzed UI/UX design for responsive layout for improved usability.
- Installing windows, software, applications, antivirus, and all developers tools needed for every PC in the company.

Marketing & Social Media Intern - Index Media Dubai, UAE - (04/2019 - 09/2019)

• Worked extensively with the marketing director and created a strategic plan in order to increase brand awareness to targeted clientele, which resulted to an increase in followers through multiple social media platforms and blog subscriptions. ● Handled design projects that required Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator. ● Used social media platforms such as Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, and Pinterest daily to promote the brand's assets.

WEBSITES, PORTOFOLIOS, PROFILES

- www.linkedin.com/in/nouran-ali
- https://github.com/na105

LANGUAGES

English Bilingual or Proficient (C2) Spanish	Arabic Bilingual or Proficient (C2)
Elementary (A2)	